<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-11-02T15:44:48-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">桃森駅 | momomori-eki</title><subtitle>language, linguistics, programming, blather</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What I’ve Been Working On</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/13/what-ive-been-working-on/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I’ve Been Working On" /><published>2019-09-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-09-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/09/13/what-ive-been-working-on</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/13/what-ive-been-working-on/">&lt;p&gt;For the past several months, I've just kept a notes file open with the title &quot;Ideas&quot; that I periodically dump stuff into. I'm a lot better at generating ideas than following through on them. I often quickly become bored or, more commonly, convince myself that my idea wasn't that great to begin with, so it should be abandoned before anyone else wastes their time. But I want to follow through on this: I'm keeping a blog, I'm going to talk about language learning somewhere other than in my various-levels-of-willing friends' gchat windows, and I'm going to write some tutorials for annoying but useful tech junk I've done. Join me on this wild ride if you dare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin, let's start with a list of links that I have categorized in my bookmarks as &quot;Stuff I Talk About All The Time.&quot; These are links I dig for because they are often relevant to what I'm thinking about or conversations I'm having, and you can probably tell a lot about me from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/cocktail-party-physics/what-does-it-take-to-change-a-mind-a-phase-transition/&quot;&gt;What Does It Take to Change a Mind? A Phase Transition&lt;/a&gt; - on the gradual buildup of influences that lead to long-term changes of heart&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://athome.nealrc.org/&quot;&gt;At Home in Japan&lt;/a&gt; - a wonderful interactive teaching tool about Japanese culture aimed at students about to go abroad for the first time, but really good info for anyone traveling or curious about Japan&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mangabrog.wordpress.com/2015/05/17/naoki-urasawa-and-hisashi-eguchi-talk-about-manga-in-the-70s-and-80s-mostly-otomo/&quot;&gt;Naoki Urasawa and Hisashi Eguchi Talk About Manga in the 70s and 80s, Mostly Otomo&lt;/a&gt; - Mostly just because of the section culminating in this quote:  “I sleep nine hours a day and look at me now — everyone else is dead!”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jacobinmag.com/2014/01/in-the-name-of-love&quot;&gt;In the Name of Love&lt;/a&gt; - &quot;Do what you love&quot; is a scam&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2017/01/23/the-heroism-of-incremental-care&quot;&gt;The Heroism of Incremental Care&lt;/a&gt; - Atul Gawande talks about a model of medical care that is less about grand solutions and more a careful buildup of helpful changes&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.totebo.com/smashing&quot;&gt;Smashing&lt;/a&gt; - a brick smashing game I was really into in high school&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mcsweeneys.net/articles/a-poem-about-your-universitys-absolute-and-unwavering-appreciation-of-its-faculty-in-spite-of-said-facultys-crap-salaries&quot;&gt;A Poem About Your University's Absolute and Unwavering Appreciation of Its Faculty in Spite of Said Faculty's Crap Salaries&lt;/a&gt; - what it says on the tin&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2012/07/ff_rabies/?pid=4216%3fsrc=longreads&amp;pid=4216?src=longreads&quot;&gt;Undead: The Rabies Virus Remains a Medical Mystery&lt;/a&gt; - rabies is fascinating&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jonkenpo.net/filtered-decks/&quot;&gt;How I Use Anki's Filtered Decks for Optimal Learning&lt;/a&gt; - the documentation on Anki filters is not great, so I end up referencing this post a lot&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonkette.com/does-jonathan-chait-think-liberals-dont-know-how-to-google&quot;&gt;Does Jonathan Chair Think Liberals Don't Know How To Google?&lt;/a&gt; - &quot;Want to know what conservatives think of immigration? Check out an op-ed from 1920!&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://postgradproblems.com/this-hipster-marriage-announcement-from-the-new-york-times-is-the-most-insufferable-yet/&quot;&gt;This Hipster Marriage Announcement From The New York Times is The Most Insufferable Yet&lt;/a&gt; - I have read this at least 8 times and it never gets old&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://seldo.com/weblog/2014/08/26/you_suck_at_technical_interviews&quot;&gt;You suck at technical interviews&lt;/a&gt; - you do! Do better, maybe?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bulletproofmusician.com/how-many-hours-a-day-should-you-practice/&quot;&gt;How Many Hours a Day Should You Practice?&lt;/a&gt; - on deliberate practice vs. hours put in&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fretna.org/openrecords/grackles.html&quot;&gt;University of Texas's War on Grackles&lt;/a&gt; - a classic in the UT dev community&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/docrocktex26/status/818486821541859328&quot;&gt;Propane Jane thread on evil/sociopathy&lt;/a&gt; - the American family plays itself out in politics at a grander scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blather" /><category term="self" /><category term="intro" /><summary type="html">For the past several months, I've just kept a notes file open with the title &quot;Ideas&quot; that I periodically dump stuff into. I'm a lot better at generating ideas than following through on them. I often quickly become bored or, more commonly, convince myself that my idea wasn't that great to begin with, so it should be abandoned before anyone else wastes their time. But I want to follow through on this: I'm keeping a blog, I'm going to talk about language learning somewhere other than in my various-levels-of-willing friends' gchat windows, and I'm going to write some tutorials for annoying but useful tech junk I've done. Join me on this wild ride if you dare.</summary></entry></feed>